<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>English Spanish Partnership Wiki</title>
    <link>https://whsesp.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on English Spanish Partnership Wiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>CC-BY-NC-SA 4.0 | WHS ESP {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://whsesp.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Spanish</title>
      <link>https://whsesp.github.io/wiki/intro-esp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whsesp.github.io/wiki/intro-esp/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the ESP Spanish Wiki! Here&amp;rsquo;s some essential knowledge to kick-start your Spanish learning journey! The first lesson is fairly long, so feel free to take breaks in between. You are expected to look up words you do not know in a dictionary.
Spanish Alphabet (el abecedario) Spanish uses the latin alphabet (a-z) plus some Spanish-only letters. Below is the Spanish alphabet and what they are called in Spanish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spanish Wiki</title>
      <link>https://whsesp.github.io/wiki-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whsesp.github.io/wiki-index/</guid>
      <description>This wiki is maintained by Walnut High School English Spanish Partnership officer team.
Social Media  Join our Discord server to learn Spanish and socialize! Join our Facebook group and Remind (code: whsespinfo) to keep track of important announcements and communicate with other members Follow us on Instagram to see Spanish tips and tricks on your feed!  Resources  Check out our wiki (see Index) Real Academia Española (RAE): Everything about the Spanish language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To be or not to be: Ser vs. Estar</title>
      <link>https://whsesp.github.io/wiki/ser-vs-estar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whsesp.github.io/wiki/ser-vs-estar/</guid>
      <description>Ser and estar are essential verbs in Spanish that mean to be in English. However, they are not interchangeable in Spanish and have specific use cases. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at these verbs in detail.
How to conjugate Ser and estar are both irregular verbs. Here&amp;rsquo;s how you conjugate them in the present indicative tense.
    Ser Estar     yo soy estoy   tú eres estás   él/ella/Ud.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>