<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spanish Wiki on English Spanish Partnership Wiki</title>
    <link>https://whsesp.github.io/wiki/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spanish Wiki on English Spanish Partnership Wiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>CC-BY-NC-SA 4.0 | WHS ESP {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://whsesp.github.io/wiki/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spaced Repetition &amp; Anki</title>
      <link>https://whsesp.github.io/wiki/anki/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whsesp.github.io/wiki/anki/</guid>
      <description>Work in Progress.
Introduction Vocabulary is an essential element of communicating in a foreign language. Without the right vocabulary, you will find yourself struggling to express your ideas efficiently and precisely. You need a minumum of 2,500 Spanish words to be able to express well in Spanish (by that I mean you will at least be able to describe the words you don&amp;rsquo;t know). It might sound like a lot, but keep in mind that a native English speaker knows more than 20,000 English words on average, and the same for native Spanish speakers (Spanish words, of course).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commands (Imperative Mood)</title>
      <link>https://whsesp.github.io/wiki/imperative/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whsesp.github.io/wiki/imperative/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Commands In our lives, it is pretty common for us to give commands to others. I&amp;rsquo;m sure we&amp;rsquo;re all familiar with these two daily ones: &amp;ldquo;Take your test&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Turn in your homework.&amp;rdquo; Commands are able to influence the actions of others, which sets the course for a very important linguistic ability.
Both English and Spanish speakers use imperatives all the time. However, there are many versions of the same command based on who you are addressing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Spanish</title>
      <link>https://whsesp.github.io/wiki/intro-to-spanish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whsesp.github.io/wiki/intro-to-spanish/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Hello, welcome to English Spanish Partnership&amp;rsquo;s Spanish wiki. Here you can find a series of tutorials on the Spanish language and occasionally on Hispanic culture.
Why learn Spanish?  Spanish is the fourth most spoken language in the world. Language learning is known to keep your mind sharp and improve your cognitive abilities, including critical thinking, memory, decision-making, etc. 20 Spanish speaking countries &amp;ndash; 20 places for travel with unique cultures and art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retelling the Past: Imperfect vs. Preterite</title>
      <link>https://whsesp.github.io/wiki/imperfect-vs-preterite/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whsesp.github.io/wiki/imperfect-vs-preterite/</guid>
      <description>Unlike English, Spanish has two types of past tenses, the imperfect and the preterite. Here&amp;rsquo;s a detailed guide to both of these tenses.
Imperfect (el imperfecto) The imperfect is appropriate when the usage applies to a time range in the past.
Imperfect Conjugation Remove the ending (-ar, -er, or -ir) to get the verb stem, then add the corresponding suffix.
-ar verbs    Subject -ar ending     yo -aba   tú -abas   él/ella/Ud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spanish Basics</title>
      <link>https://whsesp.github.io/wiki/basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whsesp.github.io/wiki/basics/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s some essential knowledge to kick-start your Spanish learning journey! This lesson is fairly long, so feel free to take breaks in between. You are expected to look up words you do not know in a dictionary.
Spanish Alphabet (el abecedario) Spanish uses the latin alphabet (a-z) plus some Spanish-only letters. Below is the Spanish alphabet and what they are called in Spanish. You should watch this short video to learn about the pronunciation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spanish Wiki</title>
      <link>https://whsesp.github.io/wiki/wiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whsesp.github.io/wiki/wiki/</guid>
      <description>This wiki is maintained by Walnut High School English Spanish Partnership officer team.
Social Media  Join our Discord server to learn Spanish and socialize! Join our Facebook group and Remind (code: whsespinfo) to keep track of important announcements and communicate with other members Follow us on Instagram (@whsespclub) to see Spanish tips and tricks on your feed!  Resources  Check out our wiki (see Index) Real Academia Española (RAE): Everything about the Spanish language.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
