<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wikis on English Spanish Partnership Wiki</title>
    <link>https://whsesp.github.io/wiki/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wikis on English Spanish Partnership Wiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>CC-BY-NC-SA 4.0 | WHS ESP {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://whsesp.github.io/wiki/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Spanish</title>
      <link>https://whsesp.github.io/wiki/intro-to-spanish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whsesp.github.io/wiki/intro-to-spanish/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Hello, welcome to English Spanish Partnership&amp;rsquo;s Spanish wiki. Here you can find a series of tutorials on the Spanish language and occasionally on Hispanic culture.
Why learn Spanish?  Spanish is the fourth most spoken language in the world. Language learning is known to keep your mind sharp and improve your cognitive abilities, including critical thinking, memory, decision-making, etc. 20 Spanish speaking countries &amp;ndash; 20 places for travel with unique cultures and art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retelling the Past: Imperfect vs. Preterite</title>
      <link>https://whsesp.github.io/wiki/imperfect-vs-preterite/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whsesp.github.io/wiki/imperfect-vs-preterite/</guid>
      <description>Unlike English, Spanish has two types of past tenses, the imperfect and the preterite. Here&amp;rsquo;s a detailed guide to both of these tenses.
Imperfect (el imperfecto) The imperfect is appropriate when the usage applies to a time range in the past.
Imperfect Conjugation Remove the ending (-ar, -er, or -ir) to get the verb stem, then add the corresponding suffix.
-ar verbs    Subject -ar ending     yo -aba   tú -abas   él/ella/Ud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spanish Basics</title>
      <link>https://whsesp.github.io/wiki/basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whsesp.github.io/wiki/basics/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s some essential knowledge to kick-start your Spanish learning journey! This lesson is fairly long, so feel free to take breaks in between. You are expected to look up words you do not know in a dictionary.
Spanish Alphabet (el abecedario) Spanish uses the latin alphabet (a-z) plus some Spanish-only letters. Below is the Spanish alphabet and what they are called in Spanish. You should watch this short video to learn about the pronunciation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
